The day after the defeat
of the Demon Lord Geld,
（リムル）
魔王ゲルド討伐の翌日
それぞれの種族の代表が集まった
representatives of each
race gathered together
to discuss what would
happen after the battle.
戦後処理の話し合いである
Chairman Rimuru Tempest,
please begin the conference.
（トレイニー）
では 議長リムル＝テンペスト
始めてください
Uh...
That Time I Got Reincarnated as a Slime
Episode 15: The Jura Forest Alliance
Uh... I've never led a meeting like this
before, so it's not my strong suit.
（リムル）
え〜 こういう会議は
初めてで 苦手なんだ
So I'll just say what's on my mind.
だから
思ったことだけを言う
I'd like you to save your
deliberations until after that.
そのあと みんなで検討してほしい
I'll start by saying this: I don't intend
to charge the Orcs with any crimes.
最初に明言するが
俺は オークに罪を問う考えはない
I know this may upset the Lizardmen,
who suffered the most casualties,
（リムル）
被害の大きい
リザードマンからしたら
不服だろうが聞いてくれ
but hear me out.
The cause of all this was
starvation due to a famine.
そもそもの原因は飢饉(ききん)による飢餓だ
Anyone, of any race, might have made
the same choices under those conditions.
同じ立場だったならば
ほかの種族の者であっても
同様の判断をしたかもしれない
Of course, this is just my
public stance on the matter.
っていうのは
まあ 建前なんだけどな
Then may we hear your personal
thoughts on it, as well?
（首領）
では…
本音を伺ってもよろしいかな？
I've taken all of the Orcs' sins upon myself.
（リムル）
オークの罪は 全て俺が引き受けた
If anyone has a complaint, bring it to me.
文句があるなら俺に言え
お… お待ちいただきたい
P-Please, wait!
Surely there is no logic to—
いくら何でも それでは道理が…
That was my promise with the Demon Lord Geld.
（リムル）
それが魔王ゲルドとの約束だ
I see.
なるほど…
However, I feel that answer
is somewhat unfair.
しかし
それは少々ずるいお答えですな
Yeah, I can see why he
wouldn't accept it so easily.
（リムル）
まあ
簡単には受け入れられないだろうな
There is one immutable rule
shared among all monsters:
（ベニマル）
魔物に共通する
唯一不変のルールがある
（ベニマル）弱肉強食
"Survival of the fittest."
The moment they faced each other,
they were both prepared for that.
立ち向かった時点で
覚悟はできていたはずだ
You guys lost your home, too.
Don't you have any complaints?
（リムル）
お前たちも里を滅ぼされているけど
文句はないのか？
I would be lying if I said we didn't,
（ベニマル）
ないと言えばウソになりますが
but if it happens again, we will not
disgrace ourselves a second time.
次があれば
同じ無様は さらしませんよ
Uh-huh...
（リムル）うむ
なるほど 正論ですな
I see... That is a fair point.
But there is one thing I must know.
ですが １つ
どうしても確認させていただきたい
What's that?
（リムル）何だ？
What will be done with the Orcs?
オークを どうなさるのですか？
You have said you will not
charge them with any crimes.
オークの罪を問わぬということは
Does that mean you intend to
accept all of their survivors?
生き残った彼ら全てを
受け入れるおつもりですか？
Even with their numbers down,
there are still 150,000 of them.
（リムル）
確かに 数は減ったとはいえ
15万のオークがいる
それでだ…
That being the case...
It may sound like some kind of dream,
夢物語のように
聞こえるかもしれないが
but I'm thinking we can all work together.
皆で協力できればと考えている
（首領）協力…
（ガビルの妹）と言いますと？
Work together?
Meaning what, exactly?
The Lizardmen will share a
clean water source and fish,
（リムル）
リザードマンからは
良質の水資源と魚を
the Goblins will offer places to live,
ゴブリンからは住む場所を
and our town will give them processed goods.
俺たちの町からは加工品を提供する
そして その見返りとして
And in return,
the Orcs will contribute labor.
オークからは
労働力を提供してもらう
（リムル）
ジュラの大森林の各種族間で
大同盟を結び
All the races of the Great Forest
of Jura will form an alliance
and build a mutually
cooperative relationship.
相互に協力関係を築く！
It'd be really cool if we could create
a nation where all races could coexist!
他種族共生国家とか出来たら
面白いと思うんだけどな
わ… 我々が
A-And you're saying we could
also take part in this alliance?
その同盟に
参加させてもらえる… と？
Well, you have nowhere else to go, do you?
（リムル）
帰る場所も 行く当ても
ないんだろ？
I have a place for you, so do some work.
居場所を用意してやるから
働けよ？
I won't tolerate slackers.
サボることは許さんよ
Yes, sir!
Of course! Of course we will!
（オークジェネラル）
もちろん… もちろんですとも
We will devote our lives to our work!
命懸けで働かせてもらいます！
うむ
We would be honored to join forces with you.
ぜひ 協力させていただきたい
Treyni-san, is that okay with you?
（リムル）
トレイニーさんも いいかな？
Certainly.
（トレイニー）よろしいでしょう
The Treants under my protection will
share the bounty of the forest, as well.
私の守護するトレント族からも
森の実りを提供いたしましょう
I believe we can alleviate the
Orcs' hunger for some time.
当面 オークたちの飢えを
癒やすことはできるかと思います
Then...
では…
As a caretaker of the forest,
森の管理者として
私 トレイニーが宣誓します
I, Treyni, hereby pledge
リムル様を ジュラの大森林の
新たなる盟主として認め…
to acknowledge Great Rimuru as the new
chancellor of the Great Forest of Jura...
Chancellor?!
（リムル）
盟主？
（トレイニー）
盟主リムル様の名の下に
...and declare the Jura Forest Alliance
ジュラの森大同盟は
成立いたしました
to be established under Chancellor Rimuru.
Uh... Er... Buh...
S-Somehow I just ended up the
chancellor of the alliance...
な… なんか
俺 盟主にされちゃったけど
Not Treyni-san?!
トレイニーさんじゃないの？
And declining really doesn't
seem like an option right now...
辞退… って そんな空気じゃないな
F-Fine, I will! I'll do it!
い… いいよ やるよ
やりますよ！
Okay, um... I guess that's how it's gonna be,
（リムル）じゃあ あの…
そういうことみたいなんで
みんな よろしく頼む！
so I'm counting on all of you!
Yes, sir!
And thus, while I was left in
an uncontrollable cold sweat,
（リムル）
こうして
冷や汗が止まらない俺を置き去りに
the Jura Forest Alliance was established.
ジュラの森大同盟は成立したのだ
You need something?
何か用か？
Even in the name of survival of the fittest,
（オークジェネラル）
弱肉強食とは言っても
憎しみは
そう簡単に割り切れるものではない
hate is not a thing that
can be resolved so easily.
For what we did to your village...
我らは オーガの里を…
I cannot apologize enough.
わびて わびきれはしない
虫のいい話であるのは
重々承知している
I realize this is a selfish request...
but please, take my head as penance
and have mercy on the others!
だが…
どうか この首１つで
ご容赦願えないだろうか！
戦いのあと 今後もリムル様の下に
在り続けたいと伝えたら
After the battle, we told Great Rimuru
that we wished to continue serving him,
and he gave us official titles.
俺たちに役職を下さった
I am a Samurai, bodyguard to Great Rimuru.
Samurai
リムル様の護衛役ですよ
秘書も兼ねてます
I'm also his secretary.
Instructor
Spy
Hakurou is an Instructor, and Souei is a Spy.
（ベニマル）
ハクロウは指南役 ソウエイは隠密
Swordsmith
Holy
Princess
Shuna and Kurobe, who remained in
the village, have titles, as well.
村に残っている
シュナとクロベエにもだ
And I received the title of Samurai General.
で… 俺は侍大将の座を賜った
Samurai
General
That puts me in charge of military affairs.
軍事を預かる役どころだ
And now that I'm in this position,
そんなとこに就いちまった以上
I can't very well rob us of a
capable fighter, now, can I?
有能な人材を 勝手に
始末するわけにはいかんだろう
I will show no mercy to any
who do wrong to Great Rimuru,
（ベニマル）
リムル様に仇(あだ)なす存在ならば
容赦はしないが
同盟に参加し 盟主と仰ぐのなら
敵ではない
but if you join the alliance and revere
him as your chancellor, we are not enemies.
あ… 仇なすなど めっそうも！
I wouldn't dream of doing him wrong!
He saved all of us.
あの方は我らを救ってくださった
従いこそすれ 敵対などありえん
I wish only to serve him.
I could never bear him ill will!
Then we are fellow servants
under the same master.
（ベニマル）
では 俺たちは同じ主(あるじ)を頂く仲間だ
Do your best to be useful to Great Rimuru.
せいぜい リムル様の役に立て
I'll accept that as your apology.
それを
わびとして受け取っておこう
父王(ふおう)ゲルドの名に誓って…
I swear on the name of my father King Geld.
Benimaru is such a gracious guy.
（リムル）
ベニマルって 器が大きいな…
I should learn from him.
俺も見習わないと
And I'll have to give that one a name,
あいつに名前を付けないとな
as the new leader of the Orcs.
新しいオークの指導者として
In hopes that you inherit the
wishes of the Orc Disaster, Geld,
（リムル）
お前は オーク･ディザスター
ゲルドの遺志を継いでもらうべく
I grant you the name "Geld."
名を“ゲルド”とする
Yes, sir!
Lead the Orcs well.
（リムル）
オークたちを
しっかり導くんだぞ
Yes, sir.
The new Orc ruler, Geld,
evolved into the Orc King.
（リムル）
新しき王ゲルドは
オークキングへと進化した
After that...
その後…
I spent ten days naming all 150,000 Orcs.
10日かけて15万
全てのオークに名前を付けた
It goes without saying that I
went into sleep mode after that.
俺がスリープモードに入ったのは
言うまでもない
I also gave the name "Abiru"
to the Lizardmen's chieftain.
ちなみに リザードマンの首領にも
“アビル”の名を
付けさせてもらった
His son, Gabiru,
その息子のガビルは
反逆の罪に問われていた
was charged with the crime of treason.
I'm sure to receive the death penalty.
（ガビル）
我が輩は死罪であろう
That's as it should be.
それでいい…
そうでなければ示しがつかん
It's the only way to set an example.
But... if there's one thing I regret...
ただ 心残りがあるとすれば…
I wish I had asked him why he saved me.
（ガビル）
聞いてみたかった
なぜ我が輩を助けてくれたのかと
A worthless fool like me...
こんな 何の価値もないマヌケを…
Raise your head.
（首領）顔を上げい
判決を申し渡す
I will now state the verdict.
I will, at least, accept the
death penalty with grace.
（ガビル）
せめて
堂々と死罪を受け入れようぞ！
ガビルを破門し 追放する
Gabiru, you will be
excommunicated and exiled.
You will never call yourself
a Lizardman again.
二度とリザードマンを名乗ることは
許さぬ
即刻 追い払うがいい
Cast him out at once!
What... did he say?!
（ガビル）
なん… だと？
You forgot something.
（護衛）忘れ物だ
ほら
Here.
Sir Gabiru!
（部下）ガビル様〜！
（ガビル）ん？
Hey!
（部下たち）
わ〜い！
ガビル様〜！
Sir Gabiru!
We've been waiting for you, Sir Gabiru!
待ってましたよ ガビル様
We were getting sick of waiting!
ったく 待ちくたびれたぜ
時は金なり
Time is money.
Wh-What are you guys doing?!
な… 何をしておるのだ お前たち！
我が輩は破門になったのだぞ
I've been excommunicated!
If you're excommunicated,
we're all excommunicated!
ガビル様が破門なら
みんな 破門ですよ
しかり
Indeed.
You guys...
（ガビル）お前ら…
バカだな
You're such fools.
Hopeless, every last one of you!
しょうがないヤツらであるな
分かった
まとめて面倒見てやろう！
Very well. I'll look after all of you.
我が輩に ついてくるがいい！
Just follow me!
That's our boy!
ヒュ〜！　さすがだぜ
かっくいい〜！
So cool!
Most definitely!
至極当然！
After you went to the trouble
of settin' all that up,
（ラプラス）
せっかく お膳立てしたのに
I bet it's killin' you that a
new Demon Lord wasn't born, huh?
新しい魔王が生まれへんかったんは
痛いんちゃうか？
（クレイマン）そうだな
Yes...
But I did get to see an interesting sight.
（クレイマン）
しかし 面白いものが見れたよ
あのスライム… どうしたものかな
Now, what shall I do about that slime?
Well, good luck to ya.
（ラプラス）せいぜい頑張ってや
If ya ever need a hand,
I'll lend ya one for cheap,
もし 協力が必要なら
格安で請け負うたるわ
Demon Lord Clayman.
魔王クレイマンはん
Three months after the
defeat of the Orc Lord,
（リムル）
オークロード討伐から３か月
the High Orcs that had evolved from the Orcs
オークから進化した
ハイオークたちは
were learning new skills in no time,
under Kaijin's instruction,
カイジンたちの指導の下
あっという間に技術を覚え
and had become a dependable work force.
頼れる労力になっていた
（リムル）
うんうん いいね　家が出来て
It's great that the houses have been built.
We've got clothing and tools, too.
服や道具も そろってきた
And...
それに…
We laid an aqueduct, too!
水道も通した！
We even have flushing toilets,
and both water and sewage systems!
なんとトイレも水洗
上下水道完備！
We're building roads, too.
道路も作っている
The stuff I learned as a general
contractor came in handy!
ゼネコン時代の知識が役に立ったな
This'll be great for commerce with
the Lizardmen and other regions.
リザードマンや各地との物流も
はかどるってもんだ
頼んでおいた風呂も
もうすぐ出来るし…
The bath I asked for will
be finished soon, too.
ん〜 楽しみだな！
I can't wait!
Right, Ranga?
なっ！　ランガ
We should all work hard together to make
this village an even greater place.
この村が
もっといい場所となるように
みんなで協力して頑張っていこうな
Yes, master! As you wish!
（ランガ）
はっ！　我が主
仰せのままに！
A place to live in peace...
（リムル）
安住の地…
ようやく俺たちの町が出来たのだ
At last, our town was complete!
But... things just couldn't be that easy.
が…
そうは問屋が卸さないのだった
（ソウエイ）
リムル様 緊急事態です
Great Rimuru, we have an emergency.
Huh?
Several hundred pegasus-mounted
knights are heading this way.
（ソウエイ）
ペガサスに乗った騎士が
数百騎
こちらに
向かっております
What?
Your Majesty, what news?
（ドルフ）王よ 暗部は何と？
The Orc Lord has been defeated,
and the war has ended.
（ガゼル）
オークロードは討伐され
戦争が終結したそうだ
（ドルフ）なんですと？
What?!
（ガゼル）
15万のオークは暴走することもなく
各地に散ったらしい
Rather than rampaging, the 150,000
surviving Orcs have scattered.
On top of that, they've evolved into High Orcs.
しかも ハイオークに進化してな
そんなことが…
That can't be...
With the participation of several
superior majin, the war came to an end.
（ガゼル）
“複数の上位魔人の参戦により
戦争は終結”
Is it safe to assume the majin
are all serving that slime?
“魔人たちは 例のスライムの
配下であると思われる”か…
One who rules over majin and
causes monsters to evolve...
魔人を従え
魔物に進化をもたらす者
If this matter is not handled
with care, this nation may fall.
此度(こたび)の件
対応を誤れば国が滅ぶやもしれぬ
あのスライムの正体
I will see just who this
slime is with my own eyes.
余 自らが
見極めてやろうではないか
（カイジン）まさか…
It can't be...
The Hero King of the Dwarves,
（リムル）
ドワーフの英雄王
ガゼル･ドワルゴ…
Gazel Dwargo...
リムル様 いかがいたしますか？
Great Rimuru, what shall we do?
I'd rather avoid fighting if possible...
（リムル）
できれば争うのは避けたいんだが…
問題ありません！
蹴散らせばよいのです
It's no problem.
We can just knock them all away.
If it comes down to a fight,
evacuate the townsfolk.
いざ戦闘になったら
住民を避難させよう
We'll buy time until then.
その間 俺たちで時間を稼ぐぞ
Right.
（カイジン）ハア ハア…
お久しぶりでございます
It is a pleasure to see you again.
久しいな カイジン
It's been a long time, Kaijin.
Yes, Majesty!
スライムか…
You are the slime?
I'll introduce myself first.
（リムル）
最初に名乗っておく
俺の名はリムルだ
My name is Rimuru.
I'm a slime, but I'd rather
you didn't call me that.
スライムだが スライム呼ばわりは
やめてもらおう
I am the chancellor of the
Jura Forest Alliance, after all.
これでも 一応は
ジュラの森大同盟の盟主なんでね
これが本性ってわけでもないんだが
こっちのほうが話をしやすいだろ？
This isn't really my true form,
but it's easier to talk to me this way, right?
So... why are you here?
で 何の用だ？
単刀直入に言おう
I'll get right to the point.
リムル 貴様を見極めに来たのだ
Rimuru, I've come to see what you truly are.
見極め？
What I truly—
I will expose your true nature with my sword!
（ガゼル）
俺の剣で
貴様の本性を見抜いてくれるわ
Since you boasted of being
the chancellor of this forest,
（ガゼル）
この森の盟主となったなどと
ホラを吹く貴様には
it seems I must teach you,
exactly, where you stand!
分(ぶん)というものを
教えてやらねばなるまい！
If that sword is more than mere decoration,
その剣が飾りでないというのなら
俺の申し出を受けるがいい
you would do well to accept my proposal.
Your Majesty, are you...
王よ まさか…
フンッ 本気で戦ってみるのが
手っとり早いであろう？
An earnest battle is the quickest
way to settle this, is it not?
All right, then. I accept.
よし その申し出を受けよう
I'll make you regret accusing me of boasting.
ホラ吹き呼ばわりしたこと
後悔させてやる
If you can defend against my
entire chain of attacks, you win.
（ガゼル）
俺の 一連の攻撃を防ぎきったら
貴様の勝ちでいい
However...
（ガゼル）ただし…
I suggest you do not underestimate the
sword skill of Master Swordsman Gazel Dwargo.
この俺 剣聖(けんせい)ガゼル･ドワルゴの剣を
甘く見ないことだ
分かった
Fine.
Very well. I will serve as
witness to this contest.
それでは
立ち会いは私が行いましょう
まさか… ドライアド？
Is that... a Dryad?
貴様をホラ吹き呼ばわりしたことは
謝罪するぞ
I willingly apologize for
accusing you of boasting.
I have a vague understanding
of the circumstances now.
それに 事情も
おぼろげながら読めたわ
じゃあ…
Then...
But that is a separate matter
from judging your true nature.
だが
貴様の人となりを知るのは別の話だ
Huh?
立会人も決まったならば
あとは剣を交えるのみ！
Now that we have a witness,
all that remains is to cross swords!
Yeah, I guess so.
ああ そうだな
I'll win this in no time and make
you explain what's going on here.
軽く勝利して 今回の件を
きっちりと説明してもらうとするわ
俺に勝てたなら
答えてやるさ
If you manage to defeat me,
you will have your answer.
（トレイニー）始め！
Begin!
Is that all the strength you have, Rimuru?
貴様の力は そんなものなのか？
リムルよ
うるさい！
Quiet! I just haven't started
taking this seriously yet.
まだ本気を出していないだけだし
慌てんな
Don't rush me.
えやあ！
（リムル）
ううむ… さすがに強いな
He's strong, all right...
But I can't just lose this.
しかし
簡単に負けるわけにはいかない
That stance...
（リムル）
あの構えは…
ゆくぞ リムル
Here I come, Rimuru!
Haze: Thunder of Heaven and Earth
Haze: Thunder of Heaven and Earth!
朧･地天轟雷(おぼろ ちてんごうらい)！
The next strike is coming... from above!
（リムル）
次が来る… 上だ！
ハハハ！
俺の剣を受け止めよったわ
You managed to stop my strike!
（トレイニー）それまで
Enough.
The winner is Rimuru Tempest.
勝者 リムル＝テンペスト！
I understand now after
crossing swords with you.
剣を交えて よく分かった
お前は邪悪な存在ではない
You are not an evil being.
What the hell?
（リムル）なんでだよ…
（ガゼル）
それにしても よくぞ俺の
“朧･地天轟雷”を見切ったものよ
I am impressed that you saw through
my Haze: Thunder of Heaven and Earth.
見事だったぞ リムル！
Well done, Rimuru.
いや 偶然だよ
Oh, that was just a coincidence.
その技 師匠が使っていて
訓練で よく打ちのめされた
My master used that move, so I
dealt with it a lot in training.
That's all, really.
それだけの話だ
What? Could it be your master was...
なんだと？
まさか その師匠というのは…
（ハクロウ）
ホッホッホ…
お見事でしたな リムル様
Excellent work, Great Rimuru.
おお… 剣鬼(けんき)殿！
The Savant!
森で迷っていた
あのときの小僧が…
You no longer look like the little
boy I found lost in the forest.
見違えましたぞ
Ah... Forgive me, Dwarf King.
いや 失礼 ドワーフ王
わし以上の剣士へと成長したようで
重畳(ちょうじょう)ですじゃ
I am overjoyed to see that you
have surpassed me with the sword.
剣鬼殿に
そう言っていただけるとは…
What an honor to hear you say that.
Hakurou was his master, huh?
（リムル）
ハクロウが師匠だったのか
You really never can tell how things
might be connected in this world.
ホント 世の中
どうつながっているのか
分からないもんだ
Great Rimuru really is amazing, huh?
Truly the best.
I see.
なるほど… オークロードを倒した
謎の魔物集団の調査だったと
You were investigating the odd assembly
of monsters that defeated the Orc Lord.
それが敵となるか 味方となるか
見極めにな
Yes, to determine whether
they were friend or foe.
リムルよ 聞きたいことがある
Rimuru, there's something I must ask you.
おう
Sure.
俺と盟約を結ぶつもりはあるか？
Have you any interest in
entering a treaty with me?
If you were to gain control of
everything in this vast forest,
（ガゼル）
お前が もしも この広大な森を
全て掌中にできたならば
you could obtain wealth and
power surpassing my own nation.
我が国をも上回る富と力を
手に入れることができよう
It would serve you well to have another
nation supporting you at such a time.
そのときに
後ろ盾となる国があれば便利だぞ
願ってもないことだが…
That would be fantastic, but...
Are you sure?
いいのか？
それは 俺たち魔物の集団を
国として認めると
That would be the same as acknowledging our
gathering of monsters as its own nation.
そう言っているのと同じだぞ？
Of course.
無論だ
それと この話
我らにとっても都合がよい
And this deal would benefit us, as well.
相互に利益がある話だ
Both sides stand to profit.
I guess I have no reason to refuse.
断る理由はないな
I gladly accept.
喜んで受けたいと思う！
よし
Good.
And what is the name of your nation?
で お前たちの国の名は
何というのだ？
Our nation's name?
（リムル）
国の名前だと？
I didn't think of that!
考えてなかった！
Um... If I take one from "Forest
of Jura" and "Rimuru Tempest"...
え〜っと… ジュラの森と
リムル＝テンペストから
名を取って…
“ジュラ･テンペスト連邦国”だ！
The Jura Tempest Federation!
ジュラ･テンペスト連邦国…
The Jura Tempest Federation?
That's our Great Rimuru!
さすがリムル様です！
（リグルド）
では 国の名前は
ジュラ･テンペスト連邦国
Then our nation shall be called
the Jura Tempest Federation,
この町の名前は
“リムル”といたしましょう！
and this town shall be called Rimuru!
Huh?!
Capital City Rimuru!
“中央都市リムル”です
Hang on, that's kinda embarrassi—
（リムル）
おいおい
それは ちょっと恥ずかしい…
Capital City Rimuru!
（シオン）
中央都市リムル！
それ以外にありません
No other name would do!
そうだな
我らの町に ふさわしい名だ
I agree. It's a perfect name for our town.
H-Huh?
It would seem that this is settled.
決まりのようだな
Yeah.
On this day, the names "the Jura Tempest
Federation" and "Capital City Rimuru"
（リムル）
この日 歴史に
ジュラ･テンペスト連邦国
were engraved in history for the first time.
そして 中央都市リムルの名が
初めて刻まれたのである
Next time, "Demon Lord Milim Attacks."
（大賢者(だいけんじゃ)）
次回「魔王ミリム 来襲」
Demon Lord Milim Attacks